

Portfolio: http://heyblackbox.com Email: heyblackbox@gmail.com

Phone: +79164218006

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/heyblackbox

Hello,

I am a Product Designer from Moscow, Russia, looking for a job in Europe, US or Canada.

My role is a crossover between product management, user experience, interaction and interface design. While doing user centered design for 5+ years, I have successfully launched and improved multiple apps for different audiences. Took responsibility for the design of a cross-platform web and mobile product with millions of users. Now I want to transfer my skills and experience into a new environment, embrace new challenges and become a better maker of digital products. I am ready to relocate.

Communication skills

- User advocate, focused on user's problem
- Can explain, articulate and protect design decisions
- Translator of concepts between managers, designers and developers
- Team player with leadership qualities
- Agile and Lean practitioner
- Involves teammates and developers into design process
- Fluent written and spoken English, beginner German, native Russian

Technical skills

- Pen and paper
- Sketch, Adobe package
- Axure RP, Flinto, Framer, and other prototyping software
- HTML, CSS, basics of Javascript

Work Experience

Zvooq (one of the leading licensed music services in Russia), 2013 — 2015 **Lead Product Designer**

- I took responsibility for design across a whole range of Zvooq sub-products: a family of mobile applications and a web service. The service has scaled to 5m users during my work as the design lead.
- Designed and shipped Zvooq Mobile a full featured streaming music app (iOS and Android) and a keystone product for a music service. Pivoted the product as the company changed business strategy. http://heyblackbox.com/zvoogmobile
- After Zvooq Mobile MVP has been verified, I have prepared and shipped the next iteration
 of web and mobile apps, which included freemium subscription model, ad-supported free
 tier and multiple payment options.
- To understand the behavior of core users, I have set new goals and data collection logic with the analytics team. Together we refined the definition of the active user.
- I have adjusted the design process to deliver early prototypes and gradually increase fidelity. Where it was necessary, synchronized design production cycles with cycles of the development team.

Dream Industries, 2010 - 2013

UX/UI Designer

- I have researched, conceptualized, designed and shipped Fonoteka mobile app the simplest and the cheapest music app with a focus on albums listening (iOS and Android). http://heyblackbox.com/fonoteka
- As a part of design team, I have launched and improved the web platform of Zvooq music service: a music streaming web app with a strong focus on discovery and social features. http://heyblackbox.com/zvooqweb
- Redesigned authentication flow, purchase and payment flows, player queue for Zvooq web platform.

Freelance, 2005 — 2010

Web and Graphic Designer

 Completed web projects in media, film and book publishing. Provided design support for music festivals.

The Creative Factory agency (acquired by Saatchi Moscow), 2003-2005

Web and Graphic Designer

- Designed rich media websites, storyboards, flash animations.
- Designed for branding and print.

Education

State University of Management, Moscow, Russia Degree in Economics, 1995-2000

Workshops:

Mobile input — Luke Wroblewski / Smashing Conf. '13 Prototyping in Axure — Fred Beecher, UX London '12 The Quest For Emotional Engagement — Stephen Anderson, UX London '12

References



Bas Grasmayer
Product Strategist, former Product Lead at Zvooq

"Over the years I worked with Alexander, he first transformed himself from someone mostly focused on desktop experiences to an excellent mobile product designer. In the process of this, he also provided great guidance to our developers on how to exactly implement features in a way that made sense on that particular platform. You would often see him sitting next to developers in order to learn more about the constraints and possibilities of these different devices and programming languages."



Davide LivraghiProject Manager at Zvoog

"Alexander is one of the most talented and devoted designers and product owners I have ever worked with. From pure design point of view, he unites brilliancy in execution across different platforms, deep understanding of usability patterns and strong commitment to plans and deadlines. From product ownership point of view, he's widely engaged in every development stage as well as in every area of the product cycle. He's extremely attentive to details and very much oriented towards maximising the quality of the user experience. Last but not least, he is a very nice and friendly person, great to work with and very fine team player."



Michael Geer COO at AnchorFree, former COO at Dream Industries

"I really enjoyed working with Alexander. He was talented, motivated and pushed for making things better around every turn. His design skills were excellent and his drive to become a better and better product manager was contagious. Highly recommended!"